# **Mason Schleu**

Software Engineer

5388 Lee St. #1211 Arvada, CO 80002 • (402) 658-6959 • mschleu231@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Agile Cyber Software Engineer with 3+ years of professional experience developing Python and C++ test code for government programs. I currently work on a fast-paced team at Lockheed Martin where my job is to test customer requirements and find and fix bugs for the cyber network device my team is tasked with designing. My three main focuses are automation, testing, and cyber security. I am a curious engineer and love to learn and use what I know to collaborate with others.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, C/C++/C#, Bash, Make, HTML/CSS, Java, Assembly, Verilog, VHDL

**Development:** Object oriented programming, debugging, sockets, data structures, performance, unit testing **Programs/Tools:** Jenkins, Atlassian suite, AWS, Microsoft Office suite, Microsoft Visual Studio, WireShark, tcpdump **Operating Systems:** Ubuntu, Red Hat, Windows, macOS, YOCTO, LXC, VMs, kernel modules, Systemd, bootloaders

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Cyber Software Engineer, Lockheed Martin – Cyber Network Interface Device (CNID)

**Active Top Secret** 

December 2018 - present // Louisville, CO

- > Developed Python framework to automate the testing of thousands of CNID requirements.
- > Designed automated cross-platform build and deploy system in Python that streamlined team's development workflow.
- > Wrote multithreaded C++ applications that integrated with Python test code using low level socket programming.
- > Collaborated with external entities such as QA and customer to facilitate efficient delivery events.

### Embedded Software Engineer, Lockheed Martin - Software Defined Satellites (SDS)

May 2018 - December 2018 // Louisville, CO

- > Developed the backend for the configuration service in C++ which handled requests from json, yaml, and ZooKeeper.
- > Wrote high quality documentation using Sphinx and Doxygen for all SDS services used by developers and users.
- > Used YOCTO to configure, build, and deploy custom Linux kernel images to target platforms.
- > Laid foundation for app manager utilizing LXC to create containers on custom embedded Linux distributions.

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant, University of Nebraska, Omaha

Fall 2016 - Spring 2018 // Omaha, NE

- > Collaborated with medical doctors and human research subjects to develop user-friendly biomechanical devices.
- > Coded mobile smartphone apps in Java and C# to quantify mobile sensor data from human motion.
- > Presented research at conferences to small audiences with wide range of backgrounds.

## Software Developer Intern, National Strategic Research Institute

Spring 2017 - Spring 2018 // Omaha, NE

- > Developed AR applications for the Microsoft HoloLens in Unity using C# to enable gesture and voice control of planes.
- > Communicated information to non-technical stakeholders via video tutorials and documentation.

#### **PROJECTS**

- > Self-taught web development and HTML/CSS and deployment using AWS to showcase my portfolio (link).
- > Team designed Android app and embedded system to track foot temperature using Bluetooth sensors.
- > Designed an 8051 based system which included RAM, ROM, LCD, keypad and various sensors. Firmware written in C.

#### **EDUCATION**

### B.S. Computer Engineering, University of Nebraska, Lincoln

2014 - 2018 // Omaha, NE - Peter Kiewit Institute

- > President of the University of Nebraska Omaha Maker Group
- > Fund for Undergraduate Scholarly Experiences (FUSE) grant recipient

2018

2017